American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIa. 1743-1806 APS.Archives.IIa APS.Archives.IIa
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Nicolas C ollin, 1803 October 27; Melanderhjelm, Daniel, Professor, 1726-1810
    Extract of letter of acknowledgment from Prof. Daniel Melanderhjelm on his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Philadelphia [sic] Philosophical Society to Jasper Carter, November 8, 1803; 5 1/2" x 6 3/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S.: Jasper Carter. Receipted bill for $25.35, for glazing and painting mineral cases.
  - The American Philos[ophical] Society to Geo[rge] Flake, November 9, 1803; 5 7/8" x 7 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by George Flake, Nov. 18, 1803. Receipted bill for $13.33, for painting certain rooms in Philosophical Hall.
  - American Philosophical Society to George Flake, November 9, 1803; 5" x 7 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: George Flake. Receipted bill for $25.10, for painting and glazing a large mineral case.
  - Letter to George Flake, 1803 November 9; American Philosophical Society.
    Receipted bill for $13.33, for painting.
  - V. DuPont de Nemours and Company to J[oh]n Vaughan, November 14, 1803; 8" x 10"; E. I. du Pont de Nemours & Company
    New York, 1 p. Concerning the necessity of paying duty on book and pamphlets received for American Philosophical Society.
  - Council of the Interior of the Batavian Republic to the American Philosophical Society, November 15, 1803; 7 7/8" x 12 1/4"; Batavian Republic
    Hague, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S.: Wenckebach. (In French.) Presents to the A.P.S.: Flora Batave, IX-XII.
  - V. DuPont de Nemours and Company to John Vaughan, November 15, 1803; 8" x 10"; E. I. du Pont de Nemours & Company
    Treasurer of A.P.S., New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Concerning duties upon books. Submits statement of accounts.
  - American Philosophical Society to W[illia]m Broome, November 19, 1803; 5 1/8" x 8 1/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by W[illia]m Broome. Receipted bill for $110, for two cases for minerals.
  - Charles Smith to John Vaughan, December 11, 1803; 6 3/4" x 8 1/8"; Smith, Charles, 1765-1836
    Lancaster, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Is sending a donation of books from Lancaster for the A.P.S. library.
  - Sam[uel] L. Mitchell to John Vaughan, December 25, 1803; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Mitchill, Samuel L. (Samuel Latham), 1764-1831
    Washington, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. In the name of the Agricultural Society of New York, acknowledges the receipt of A.P.S. Transactions, V.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Dec. 26, 1803; 10x8; Du Pont, Eleuthère Irénée, 1771-1834
    Wilmington, A.L.S. 2p.,add.and end. In French. Concerning books from France and promising to complete sets.
  - G. Wilkinson to Adam Seybert, December 26, 1803; 7 1/2" x 9 1/4"; Wilkinson, G.
    Secretary to the A.P.S., Sunderland, Durham County, 3 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Wishes to be proposed a member of the American Philosophical Society. Refers to B.Franklin. FILM54-63 FRAME33
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 29, 1803; 7 1/4" x 9"; Roxburgh, William, 1751-1815
    Calcutta, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Acknowledges APS Transactions; also his election to membership. Skeleton of the elephant. Asiatick society only literary society in India, to his knowledge.
  - Letter to W. Roxburgh, (1803) Sunday; Moore, R[ichard Channing], 1762-1841
    Announces to Roxburgh that the skeleton prepared for him will be shipped at the beginning of December [1803].
  - Miscellaneious notes pertaining to books received in the A.P.S. Library., (1803?-1839?); American Philosophical Society.
    Miscellaneous notes on books received in the A.P.S. Library.
  - Jane Aitken to John Vaughan, June 30-August 16, 1803-1804; 7 1/8" x 9 7/8"; Aitken, Jane, 1764-1832
    Dr., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Jane Aitken, J[oh]n Vaughan. Statement of accounts covering period indicated above.
  - Letter to Thomas C. James:, Jan. 3, 1804; 10x8; Madison, James, 1749-1812
    Williamsburg, A.L.S. 1p.and add., end. Acknowledges election to membership in the APS. (Madison had been reported elected, Jan.21,1780, in Penna.Packet, Jan.27, 1780.)
  - The Insurance Company of North America to John Vaughan, January 18, 1804; 7 1/2" x 7 7/8"; Insurance Company of North America
    Treasurer of A. P. S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Cha[rle]s P. Heath. Receipt for $18, for insurance on Philosophical Hall and library for the year 1804.
  - John Vaughan to Yorke and Lippincott, January 19, 1804; 4 5/8" x 6 1/4"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by Yorke and Lippincott. Receipt bill for $28.60, for a geography ($6.60), and bookcase ($22).
  - American Philosophical Society to James Thackara, January 20, 1804; 5 5/8" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by Ja[me]s Thackara. Receipted bill for $3.50, for paper and printing 100 certificates.
  - Letter to Thos. T. Hewson, Jan. 20, 1804; 8" x 10"; Jefferson, Thomas, pres. U.S., 1743-1826
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Acknowledges re-election [as president of the A.P.S.]. Comments on the Louisiana territory. Printed: A.P.S. Proc.,v.22,pt.3,347 Bur. of rolls, v.6,215-S.1,v.10,6. FILM 199 FRAME 171
  - List of Donations, 1804 Jan. 20; American Philosophical Society.
    List of book donations to the A.P.S. Library.
  - Letter to J. Vaughan, Jan. 26, 1804; 7 1/4" x 9"; Roxburgh, William, 1751-1815
    Calcutta, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Comments on Barton's Elements of botany. Skeleton of the elephant.
  - [American Philosophical Society] to C[harles] W[illson] Peale, January, 1804; 7 1/2" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, --, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by C.W.Peale. Receipted bill for $20.96, for stove in Philosophical Society's rooms.
  - Letter to Jonathan Williams, Elizabeth Town, Feb. [6], 1804; 9" x 7 1/2"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Has written to Mr. Stewart (sic) about the portrait [of Washington ?]. Cf. APS Minutes, April 15, May 20,1803; Report of Com., May 6,1803.
  - Louis Valentin to the [American] Philosophical Society, February 10, 1804; 5 3/8" x 7"; Valentin, Louis, 1758-1829
    Marseille, 2 pp. A.L.S. Sends a second copy of his Treatise on Yellow Fever to the A.P.S., having been informed that the first copy sent was lost.
  - Report of the committee appointed to lay before the Society a plan for the future publication of their Transactions, February 17, 1804; 8 1/8" x 9 15/16"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 4 pp. and endorsements. D.S.: R[obert] Patterson and four others. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 348.
  - American Philosophical Society to Jane Aitken, February 20, December 10, 1804; 7 1/4" x 7 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by Jane Aitken, December 31, 1804. Statement of accounts totaling $28.50, the sum being credited to account of the late Robert Aitken.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 25, 1804; 8" x 9 3/4"; L'Hommedieu, Ezra, 1734-1811
    Albany, L.S. 1p. and add., end. On behalf of the Society for the promotion of agriculture, arts and manufactures, acknowledges APS Transactions.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 25, 1804; 8" x 9 3/4"; Society for the Promotion of Agriculture, Arts and Manufactures
    Albany, L.S.: Ezra L'Hommedieu 1p. and add., end. Acknowledges APS Transactions.
  - [Marquis de] Lafayette to the President of the A.P.S., February 26, 1804; 7 1/8" x 9"; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert de Motier, marquis de, 1757-1834
    La Grange, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S. a work by [A. L. C. Destutt de] Tracy, Analyse raisonnée de l'origine de tous les cultes, 2 vols. Microfilm no. 191. FILM199 FRAME342
  - Report of committee on [B.S] Barton's paper on language, March 2, 1804; 8x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Nicholas Collin and Peter S. DuPonceau. 1p. and end. Cf. Minutes, p. 349. Printed: Trans.,o.s.,vol.VI, 145ff.
  - W. Lewis to Thomas Jefferson, March 7, 1804; 7 1/2" x 11 7/8"; Lewis, William?, 1745?-1822
    President of A.P.S., Campbell County, Virginia, 3pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Donates a bone and some rocks to A.P.S. See Minutes, April 6, 1804, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 350. FILM 199 FRAME 117
  - Receipt to Josiah Humphreys, Jr., 1804 March 10; American Philosophical Society.
    Receipt for member subscription.
  - [List of material] presented by the minister of polit[ical] oeconomy of Batavian Republick [to the American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia], April 7, 1804; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Batavian Republic
    1 p. and endorsement. D. Unsigned. Handwriting of John Vaughan(?).
  - Report of the committee... on the subject of erecting a timepiece, April 13, 1804; 8" x 9 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 3 pp. and endorsements. D.S.: R[obert] Patterson, J[oh]n Vaughan, F[rancis] Nichols. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 351.
  - Report of the committee upon the meteorological paper of William Dunbar, April 20, 1804; 8 1/8"x 10"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: James Mease, W[illia]m Barnwell. Paper reported as worthy of publication.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the letter of William Lewis, of Campbell county, Virginia, April 20, 1804; 8 1/16" x 10"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] Patterson, R[obert] Hare, jr. Concerning minerals to be presented to Mr. Peale agreeably to the request of Mr. Williams Lewis. Mentions T.Jefferson. FILM 199 FRAME 343
  - American Philosophical Society to John Gullen, April 25, 1804; 4 1/8" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by John Gullen. Receipted bill for $3, for stone step placed at door of Rittenhouse Observatory.
  - American Philosophical Society to George Hyde and Company, April 26, 1804; 4 7/8" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by George Hyde & Co. Receipted bill for $3.92, for drawing paper.
  - The American Philosophical Society to Mary Wells,Dr., Philadelphia, April 26, 1804; 5 1/4" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by Mary Wells. Receipted bill for $10, for making 600 pasteboard mineral cases.
  - Philadelphia [sic] Philosophical Society to F. Brown, May 4, 1804; 4 1/2" x 7 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by F. Brown. Receipted bill for $2.50, for printing on 100 certificates of election.
  - Report of committee on publication, May 18, 1804; 7-1/2x6; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Jn.Vaughan and R.Patterson. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.357.
  - Am[erica]n Philos[ophical] Society to Rob[ert] Dawson, June 8, 1804; 5" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by Esther Dawson. Receipted bill for $2.10, for 3 1/2 yards of oilcloth.
  - Sam[ue]l Miller to John Vaughan, June 14, 1804; 8" x 9 1/2"; Miller, Samuel
    New York, 2 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Sends to the A.P.S. a copy of his Retrospect of the Eighteenth Century.
  - W[illiam] Vaughan to John Redman Coxe, June 15, 1804; 7 13/16" x 9 11/16"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. ---- Duplicate of above. In re Haarlem Philosophical Transactions.
  - Gouverneur and Kemble to John Vaughan, June 17, 1804; 7 1/2" x 9"; Gouverneur & Kemble
    New York, 1 p. and endorsement. L.Signed: Gouverneur & Kemble. Advising that the packet from the Asiatic Society has not arrived.
  - Philadelphia [sic] Philosophical Society to George Flake, June 19, 1804; 4 1/2" x 7 7/8 "; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by George Flake. Receipted bill for $68.17, for painting Philosophical Hall.
  - Report of the committee appointed to consider and report additional rules for the preservation of order at the meetings of this board, June 22, 1804; 7 7/8" x 13"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. D.S.: Peter S. DuPonceau, J[oh]n Vaughan, J[onathan] B. Smith.
  - Report of the committee appointed to devise means of more effectually carrying into execution the objects of the Magellanic fund, June 22, 1804; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] Patterson, C[aspar] Wistar, B[enjamin] S[mith] Barton, John Redman Coxe. Film No. 277
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s T. Hewson, secretary American philosophical society, June 26, 1804; 7 1/4" x 9"; Rumford, Benjamin, Graf von, 1753-1814
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Acknowledges election to membership. Cf. Minutes of Sept. 21, 1804.
  - Joseph Priestley to J[ohn] Vaughan, Treasurer of A.P.S., June 30, 1804; 3 1/4" x 7 3/4"; Priestley, Joseph
    Philadelphia, ? died Feb 1804 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S. Receipt of $64.31, for designated English journals.
  - American Philosophical Society to Rich[ar]d Vidler, June, 1804; 4 1/2" x 7 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. Receipted by Rich[ar]d Vidler. Receipted bill for $5, for repairing brick work under steps of museum.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 2, 1804; 9-1/2x7; Du Pont de Nemours, Victor Marie, 1767-1827
    New York, L.S. 1p.,add.and end. Agrees that French journals sent to the APS should be sent via Bordeaux.
  - William Thornton to John Vaughan, Washington, July 6, 1804; 8" x 9 3/4"; Thornton, William, 1759-1828
    2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Orders a complete set of A.P.S. Transactions "for the office of State." Visit of [Alexander von Humboldt] to Washington. Has not yet attended to the Magellanic premiums.
  - Letter to the members of the Philosophical society of Philadelphia, July 9, 1804; 6" x 8", 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Godoy, Manuel de, príncipe de la Paz, 1767-1851
    Madrid, L.S: El Principe de la Paz. 1p. and end. In Spanish. (Accompanied by translation. 1p.) Acknowledges election to membership, and receipt to volumes of the Transactions. Cf. Minutes - March 15, 1805.
  - Am[eric]an Philo[sophica]l Soc[iet]y to W[illia]m Broome, July 13, 1804; 8" x 10"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by W[illia]m Broome. Recepited bill for $16.07, for carpentry work from November 1, 1803 to July 16, 1804.
  - Letter to William Hembel, July 16, 1804; 10x8; Patton, Tristram
    Virginia, L.S. 2p.and drawing, end. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Natural philosophy, vol.1, no. 40.) Concerning sulphate of magnesia. Cf. Minutes, p.360.
  - Report of the committee appointed to examine... a manuscript... journal by Thomas Sullivan, July 20, 1804; 7 13/16" x 8 1/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Peter S. DuPonceau, B[enjamin] S[mith] Barton. Recommend that the journal be preserved in the library. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 359.
  - J. B. Smith to John Vaughan, July 20, 1804; 7 3/8" x 9 5/8"; Smith, J. B.
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. L. Relative to curious moss presented to A.P.S. See Minutes, July 20, 1804, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 359.
  - W[illiam] Short to Jonathan Williams, July 24, 1804; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Short, William, 1759-1849
    New York, 2 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - J[onathan] Williams to John Vaughan, July 26, 1804; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Williams, Jonathan, 1750-1815
    Elizabeth Town, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning the election of [William] Short to membership in the A.P.S.
  - J[ohn] Eliot to John Vaughan, July 27, 1804; 7 3/8" x 9"; Eliot, John, 1754-1813
    Boston, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Donates [Massachusetts] Historical Collections, IX, to the A.P.S. Sends one or two pamphlets to Mr. Vaughan.
  - John Vaughan to Samuel F. Bradford, July 27, 1804; 5" x 7 5/8"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement, D. Receipted by J. Anderson. Receipted bill for $8.25, for lamp and wicks.
  - Turpin to John Vaughan, August 1, 1804; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Turpin, P. J. F. (Pierre Jean François), 1775-1840
    Treasurer of the A.P.S., Bordeaux, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French). Announcing his arrival and his intention to attend closely to commissions for the Society.
  - Nichol[as] Collin to J[ohn] Vaughan, August 3, 1804; 6 1/2" x 7 13/16"; Collin, Nicholas, 1746-1831
    Librarian of the A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Reasons for his delay in collecting "extracts from the Records of the Swedish Churches" relative "to the objects of this society."
  - John Bioren and Tho[mas] L. Plowman to [John] Vaughan, August 6, 1804; 7 1/4" x 8 7/8"; Bioren, John, 1773-1835
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. 3d. per. N. Presents to A.P.S.: [Alexander] Stephens, wars of the French Revolution, 2v.
  - W[illia]m Vaughan to John Redman Coxe, August 16, 1804; 7 3/4" x 12 1/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    Secretary of A.P.S., London, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S. Charges on two boxes of books sent to A.P.S. Enclosed in W[illia]m Vaughan to John Redman Coxe, August 25, 1804.
  - Report of committee to settle lease with C.W. Peale, Aug. 17, 1804; 7-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.Patterson, Jn. Vaughan and J.Mease. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.360.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the paper of Dr. [Hugh] Williamson on the fascinating power of serpents, August 17, 1804; 7 15/16" x 9 11/16"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: J[ohn] Church, R[obert] Hare, Jr., Tho[ma]s T. Hewson. Publication in Transactions recommended.
  - American Philos[ophical] Society to John Conrad and Company, August 18, 1804; 4 1/2" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by John Conrad & Co. Receipted bill for $6, for [Richard] Kirwan's Elements of Mineralogy, 2v.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], Aug. 18, 1804; 9x7-1/2; Finlay, William M.
    Beaufort, S.C., A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. (see Ms.Comm.to APS. Math and Astronomy, vol.1, no.50.) Sends letter to the APS. For letter, see same to same, second letter of same date.
  - W[illiam] Vaughan to John Redman Coxe, August 25, 1804; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    Secretary of A.P.S., London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding Transactions of Batavian Philosophical Society sent to A.P.S. See Minutes, November 2, 1804, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 364.
  - W[illiam] Vaughan to John Redman Coxe, August 25, 1804; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    Secretary of A.P.S., London, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. Duplicate. Regarding Transactions of Batavian Philosophical Society sent to A.P.S. See Minutes, November 2, 1804, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 364.
  - Edward Farris to John Vaughan, August 27, 1804; 3 3/4" x 8"; Farris, Edward
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S. Receipt for $16, paid to Mr. Farris for copying the journals of Thomas P. Smith.
  - The [American] Philosophical Society to Pat[rick] Lyon, August 28, 1804; 5 1/2" x 8 1/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Unsigned. Bill for $3.75, for iron scrapers.
  - W[illia]m Maclure to the [American] Philosophical Society, September 3, 1804; 4 9/16" x 7 7/16"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. 3d. per. N. Presents to the A.P.S., a copy of [Dominique Vivant] Denon, Travels in Egypt. See Pro., XXII pt. 3, 368.
  - Royal Institution of Great Britain to John Vaughan, September 4, 1804; 7 3/16" x 8 7/8"; Royal Institution of Great Britain
    Librarian to the A.P.S., London. 2 pp. and endorsements. A.L.S.: J. P. Auriol, Secy. Presents to the A.P.S.: the Journals of the Royal Institution hitherto published; also the bye-laws and the regulations of the library. Mentions T.Jefferson. FILM199 FRAME344
  - Am[erica]n Ph[ilosophical] Soc[iet]y to Aug[usti]n Bousquet, September 5, 1804; 4 3/4" x 7 5/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by Aug[usti]n Bousquet. Receipted bill for $5.54, for 67th part of French Encyclopédie.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Sept. 10, 1804; 10x8; Du Pont de Nemours, Pierre Samuel, 1739-1817
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. In French. Forwards French journals to the APS. Film 403 Frame 52
  - Letter to Dr. Barton, Sept.10, 1804; 8" x 9 1/2"; Banks, Joseph, 1743-1820
    Soho Square, Extract from L. 1p. and end. Acknowledges APS Transactions. Royal Society requests that an agent be authorized to receive its Transactions which are to be forwarded to America. Cf. Minutes of Nov.2,1804.
  - Tristram Patton to William Hembel, September 17, 1804; 7 7/8" x 12 3/4"; Patton, Tristram
    Jr., Second Creek, Monroe County, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Respecting fossil bones intended for a museum. Mentions T.Jefferson. FILM 199 FRAME 345
  - Da Costa to [the American Philosophical Society], September 21, 1804; 7 3/8" x 9 1/4"; Da Costa, Francis
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. Analysis of sample of lead ore from Mill Grove Farm, Perkiomen Creek, donated to A.P.S. See Minutes, September 21, 1804.
  - Letter to J[oh]n Vaughan, Sept. 22, 1804; 9x7-1/2; Pinckney, Charles Cotesworth, 1746-1825
    Charlestown, L. 2p.and end. Extract. (see Ms.comm. to the APS. Trade. navigation, etc., no. 39.) Concerning the destruction of pine trees by a worm. Cf. Minutes, p. 362. On Same sheet is a memorandum by J.Vaughan; Oct. 5, 1804.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 23, 1804; 10x8; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, A.L.S.: Delambre. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Thanks for publications. Refers to Du Pont (de Nemours).
  - Rob(ert) R. Livingston to ----, September 23, 1804; 7 1/4" x 9 1/8"; Livingston, Robert R., 1746-1813
    Paris, 2 pp. L.S. Forwards work upon meteors to A.P.S. Observations upon treatment of Seal-skins.
  - American Philos[ophical] Society to Jane Aitken, September 28, 1804; 3 1/2" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by Jane Aitken. Receipted bill for $2, for pasting three surveys of Chesapeake and Delaware canal upon muslin.
  - Memorandum on the destruction of pine trees by a worm, Oct. 5, 1804; 9x7-1/2; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, A.D.S. 1p. (See Ms.Comm. to the APS. Trade, navigation, etc., no. 39.) On same sheet as letter from C.C.Pinckney to J.Vaughan; Sept. 22, 1804.
  - Letter to Leonard Snowden, Oct. 8, 1804; 10x8; Chipchase, John
    A.L.in 3rd.P. 4p.,end. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Natural philosophy, vol. 1, no. 39.) Sends extract from the Gentleman's magazine for June 1803 on meteors. Cf. Minutes, p.349.
  - C. D. Ebeling to John Vaughan, October 8, 1804; 7 3/8" x 9"; Ebeling, Christophe Daniel, 1741-1817
    Librarian to the A.P.S., Hamburg, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning [A.P.S.] Transactions sent to Jena. Introducing Dr. Schoettler, who wishes to establish practice in a German community. FILM 403 FRAME 162
  - R[obert] Hare, jr., to John Vaughan, librarian of the A.P.S., October 11, 1804; 3 3/8" x 7 7/8"; Hare, Robert, 1781-1858. American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1p. D.S. Receipt for W[illiam] Dunbar, Supplement to the memoir on the Mississippi.